# 哈喽 大家好
Hey, guys!
# 今天我们开车去一个离我们富顺有半个多小时的一个地方
Today we are driving to a place half an hour away from Fushun.
# 准备增加一个工作室
We are planning to open a new studio.
# 现在这个工作室不够宽
Our current studio is not spacious enough.
# 后面想加一些其它的拍摄的一些菜加不了
We were unable to cook certain dishes in this studio.
# 所以今天去看一个大一点的厨房
So today I will show you a bigger kitchen studio.
# 是以前一个农家乐
It used to be an agritainment.
# 农家乐的一个厨房
One of its kitchens.
# 现在去把它租下来
And we rented it,
# 然后拍更多的美食
so we can make more videos.
# 这里什么都好位置也够宽也够大也够高
It's tall and spacious.
# 唯一一点就是太远有点偏僻
But it is a little too far away from the city.
# 其实也好 拍的时候也不吵
It's not a big deal actually. It's quite.
# 就像我们现在工作室一样随时
Unlike our current studio,
# 门口有叫卖凉糕啊 凉面呀叫得很大声
There are always street vendors loudly advertising their products outside.
# 他叫卖的时候我们就只有停下来等他走了我们再拍
We have to pause and wait until they leave.
# 所以这样也是挺麻烦的
It is annoying.
# 越是到农村这个空气就越是好
Air is fresher in the countryside.
# 就是按照酒店里面那种地板砖防滑的
Just like in commercial kitchens, the floor will be paved with non-slip tiles.
# 要求有些啥子 技术方面呀或者
Do you have any other technical requirements?
# 没得啥子要求的啊
Not really.
# 就是把它铺平就可以了
Just make them flat.
# 就是这个这里如果是地板砖铺起来了
The only thing is that after paving the tiles,
# 这个可能要往上面提
you might want to lift this up as well.
# 这个要把它垫起来
Lift this up.
# 就相当于以这个为台子样
So we basically take this as a platform.
# 其它有啥子（要求）打灶啊这些
Any other requirements on things like the kitchen stove?
# 这上面帮我涂黑色的漆
Paint the ceiling black please.
# 上面涂黑的
Black on top.
# 黑油漆刷
Black?
# 嗯就是过刷
Yes, just paint it black.
# 这个墙要弄起
What about the walls?
# 墙不弄
Just leave them as they are.
# 墙上面喷不喷漆的话
You don't want to paint the walls?
# 你刷的时候注意到
Pay attention when you are painting.
# 餐厅这黑一坨 那儿花的（不好看）
Black here and other colors there? It won't look good.
# 你先刷中间撒 然后边边
Start from the middle first, then move on to the sides...
# 这儿可能有接近一百个平方
This place is about a hundred square meters.
# 这里是6米 我拉过的
Here is six meters. I have measured it.
# 这边是6米
Yea, six meters.
# 这边好像
And here,
# 数砖嘛数砖
you can just count the tiles.
# 哦 数砖都数得出来
Oh yes! I can just count the tiles.
# 6米多 可能有6米3
About 6 meters, maybe 6.3 meters.
# 你这个掉不掉哦
Will that fall off?
# 哪个哦
Which one?
# 那水泥起缝了
The concrete is cracking.
# 它掉不掉下来嘛
It will fall off.
# 害怕给它敲了
We will replace it.
# 反正给它算工程嘛 算一哈
It's part of the work.
# 包工包料
Labor and material included.
# 你是整这地方做啥子安
What do you want to do with this place?
# 我就是拍炒菜那个位置小了
I am just filming cooking videos. The old studio is too small.
# 宽度不够 这里6米就够了撒
It's not wide enough. Here, six meters is enough.
# 我那边才3米多点 太窄了
The old studio is only three meters wide, which is way too narrow.
# 4吨水泥
Four tons of concrete.
# 4吨噶
Four tons?
# 嗯
Yea.
# 河沙10 吨啊
Sand, ten tons?
# 嗯
Yes.
# 这哈是砖 砖130张
130 pieces of tiles.
# 130张啊
130 tiles?
# 1250 1300张嘛
About 1250, 1300 tiles.
# 1350
1350.
# 1350就是
Yes, 1350.
# 油漆等会我去问了来
As for the paints, I will ask them later.
# 那个也不晓得要得到好多大概
I am not sure how much we need.
# 100个平方的油漆给他说看要得到好多量
I asked how much paint we need for a 100 square meter's room.
# 就这个人工费
And the cost of labor,
# 人工好多
is a lot.
# 人工费这个要40一个平方
It's like 40 RMB per square meter.
# 40嘎 100个就是4000块钱是不是
40? 100 square meter will cost 4000 RMB.
# 水泥500左右撒
The concrete is about 500 RMB.
# 500一吨噶
500 RMB per ton.
# 500加点油费
500 plus shipping fee.
# 他包运哒
Isn't it free shipping?
# 哪里要包运哦 不得
No, absolutely not.
# 500 4吨
500 RMB, 4 tons.
# 四五二千
Four times five-hundred makes two thousand.
# 2300嘛
2300 RMB?
# 2300拿得到撒
Can we get them for 2300 RMB though?
# 300块钱（油费）差不多
300 RMB shipping fee should be enough.
# 刚才我舅舅叫的2个师傅在这里看了一下
Earlier, the construction team that my uncle invited came and checked this place.
# 这里总共有90个平方
We have 90 squre meters here.
# 加上地板砖加上人工所有算下来大概一万五左右
Counting floor tiles and labor cost we need about 15000 RMB.
# 就是材料什么的
Like materials and other stuff.
# 这里以前是一个山庄的厨房
This place used to be a restaurant's kitchen.
# 他们的厨房经营不下去了就没有做了
But then the restaurant closed down.
# 然后这里可以看一下这个厨具
We can see these pieces of equipment
# 已经荒废了很久了都已经生锈了
have already gotten rusty.
# 然后还有一些衣服不要的
Some old clothes here
# 其它的还好这里投入一点精力来打理一下
We need some time to renovate this place.
# 隔壁还有餐厅
There is also an restaurant next door.
# 餐厅的话下期视频给你们看一下
I will show you the restaurant in the next video.
# 然后这里就等着师父明天买材料进来就可以做了
We just need to wait for the workers to get all the materials they need and then we can start.
# 好了 本期视频就到这里了 拜拜
That's all for this video, see you!